Dmytro Korenko - Software Engineer | Full Stack Developer

I'm an experienced full stack engineer specializing in scalable web applications. I primarily focus on TypeScript-based full-stack projects (Nest.js, React, Next.js).

Currently, I'm a Lead Front-End Engineer at Roll'n'Code. I contribute to the creation and maintenance of UI components that power EGW Writings frontend, ensuring our platform meets web accessibility standards and best practices.

Check out my portfolio and let's build something amazing together!

Email: text@mail.com

GitHub: https://github.com/korenko-git LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/korenko-git/

Website: https://leetcode.com/u/korenko-git/

Work Experience

Front - End Developer

Roll'n'Code | 2021-01 - Present

Working on Ellen G.'s interactive website. White Estate with gamification elements. EGW Writings contains a custom Study Center, Cloud Synchronization of all devices, Audiobooks, online and offline advanced Search and support of more than 100 languages. Collaborated closely with the design team to implement pixel-perfect layouts and user flows. Implemented CI/CD pipelines and Dockerized the application. Participated in code reviews, hiring processes and mentoring new developers.

Skills: React, TypeScript, Next.js, Docker, Jest, Redux, Tailwind, GraphQL, Selenium

Full - Stack Developer

krgaz | 2019-03 - 2021-12

Contributed into development of custom CRM system for a leading gas delivery company in the Ukraine. Designed fronted, utilizing technologies like React, jQuery. Participated in the backend development using PHP, Django, and MariaDB. Developed account management system, user roles, and permissions. Implemented integrations with third-party services, such as Google Roads. Worked on the mobile application using React Native.

Skills: React, PHP, Python, Laravel, Django, jQuery, MySQL, WordPress, ReactNative

Education

Master of Computer Science

Stanford University | 2017-09 - 2019-06

Advanced studies in distributed systems and cloud computing

Skills: AWS, Node.js, Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform, Python, Microservices, CI/CD, MongoDB,

Redis, ELK Stack, Prometheus, Grafana

Bachelor of Information Technology

Massachusetts Institute of Technology | 2013-09 - 2017-06

Focus on software engineering and web technologies

Skills: AWS, Node.js, Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform, Python, Microservices, CI/CD, MongoDB,

Redis, ELK Stack, Prometheus, Grafana

Certificates

• AWS Certified Developer (Amazon Web Services) - 2023-01

• React Advanced (Meta) - 2022-06

Projects

Online Learning Platform

Development of an interactive platform for online learning with support for video lessons and testing.

Technologies: React, Node.js, MongoDB, WebRTC, Redux, Express.js, Jest, WebSockets, AWS S3,

Links: Source Demo

Task Management System

Creation of a system for project and task management with real-time updates.

Technologies: TypeScript, React, Socket.io, PostgreSQL, NestJS, Docker, GraphQL, Material-UI,

Jest, CI/CD

Links: Source Demo